[{"question": "Suppose you monitor biodiversity using 1 by 1 metre quadrats and measure environmental variables (e.g. temperature and salinity) for each location. Which DwC term links the species occurrences with the abiotic measurements?", "answers": ["measurementType", "eventID", "occurrenceID", "parentEventID"], "answer_text": "The eventID from the Event Core links the species occurrences to the sampling events and the abiotic measurements to the sampling events.", "correct_answer": 1}, {"question": "Which DwC term links your occurrence record and your biotic measurements (e.g. body length, wet weight biomass, counts)?", "answers": ["parentEventID", "measurementTypeID", "occurrenceID", "eventID"], "answer_text": "The occurrenceID is a unique ID for each species occurrence and is used to link the occurrence extension (or occurrence core) with the extended MeasurementOrFact extension.", "correct_answer": 2}, {"question": "Your dataset represents a multiple station survey holding species occurrences and environmental data for each station. You also have the sampling protocol for each station and sample. How many files will you have after organising this dataset into the OBIS-ENV-DATA format?", "answers": ["OBIS cannot deal with all these data types", "Two", "Three", "Five", "One"], "answer_text": "One for the sampling events (eventCore), one for the species occurrences (occurrence extension), one for the measurements and sampling facts (extended MeasurementOrFact extension).", "correct_answer": 2}, {"question": "The terms measurementType and measurementTypeID are part of the ExtendedMeasurementorFact Extension file.", "answers": ["True", "False"], "answer_text": "", "correct_answer": 0}, {"question": "Which DwC term links your occurrence record and your biotic measurements (e.g. body length, wet weight biomass, counts)?", "answers": ["parentEventID", "measurementTypeID", "occurrenceID", "eventID"], "answer_text": "The occurrenceID is a unique ID for each species occurrence and is used to link the occurrence extension (or occurrence core) with the extended MeasurementOrFact extension.", "correct_answer": 2}, {"question": "What does it mean when individualCount has the following value?", "answers": [{"NULL": ["100 individuals were observed", "There is no information on individualCount", "The species was not found, the occurrenceStatus should be set to 'Absent'"]}, {"0": ["100 individuals were observed", "There is no information on individualCount", "The species was not found, the occurrenceStatus should be set to 'Absent'"]}, {"100": ["100 individuals were observed", "There is no information on individualCount", "The species was not found, the occurrenceStatus should be set to 'Absent'"]}], "answer_text": "", "correct_answer": {"NULL": 1, "0": 2, "100": 0}}, {"question": "only have the country as location information, no coordinates. What should I do?", "answers": ["Add the country name in the DwC:location. OBIS automatically adds the coordinates", "Add the country's EEZ name in DwC:country. OBIS automatically adds the coordinates", "Provide the midpoint and radius from the countries EEZ (available in marineregions.org) in DwC:decimalLatitude, DwC:decimalLongitude and DwC:coordinateuncertaintyInMeters and provide the country EEZ name in DwC:location and add the marineregions ID (MRGID) in DwC:locationID", "Add the ISO country code in DwC:country. OBIS automatically adds the coordinates"], "answer_text": "The correct answer is: Provide the midpoint and radius from the countries EEZ (available in marineregions.org) in DwC:decimalLatitude, DwC:decimalLongitude and DwC:coordinateuncertaintyInMeters and provide the country EEZ name in DwC:location and add the marineregions ID (MRGID) in DwC:locationID", "correct_answer": 2}, {"question": "The scientificNameID can be found in WoRMS", "answers": ["True", "False"], "answer_text": "", "correct_answer": 0}, {"question": "If you have data about dolphin sightings, which vocabulary should you use for the DwC term: basisOfRecord?", "answers": ["LivingSpecimen", "Present", "PreservedSpecimen", "HumanObservation"], "answer_text": "", "correct_answer": 3}, {"question": "My dataset contains date ranges. How shall I publish this in OBIS?", "answers": ["Provide the dates as DwC:startEventDate and DwC:endEventDate", "Provide the start and end date in DwC:eventDate with a / separator.", "Provide the mid-date."], "answer_text": "", "correct_answer": 1}, {"question": "When a Scientific Name is in WoRMS, but the taxonomic status is unaccepted (synonym), I can use the WoRMS LSID of the unaccepted name.", "answers": ["True", "False"], "answer_text": "OBIS indeed uses the information from WoRMS and will add occurrences to the current accepted name.", "correct_answer": 0}, {"question": "When a Scientific Name is in WoRMS, but the taxonomic status is unaccepted (synonym), I can use the WoRMS LSID of the unaccepted name.", "answers": ["True", "False"], "answer_text": "OBIS indeed uses the information from WoRMS and will add occurrences to the current accepted name.", "correct_answer": 0}, {"question": "The dataset you are processing contains the taxon name Dinophysis intermedia (scientificnameID = urn:lsid:marinespecies.org:taxname:844470) for which the accepted name is Dinophysis fortii (scientificnameID urn:lsid:marinespecies.org:taxname:109624). What do you fill out as scientificName and scientificNameID?", "answers": ["<ul><li>scientificName: the accepted name Dinophysis fortii</li><li>scientificNameID: the LSID of the unaccepted name urn:lsid:marinespecies.org:taxname:844470</li></ul>", "<ul><li>scientificName: the unaccepted name Dinophysis intermedia</li><li>scientificNameID: the LSID of the unaccepted name urn:lsid:marinespecies.org:taxname:844470</li></ul>", "<ul><li>scientificName: the unaccepeted name Dinophysis intermedia</li><li>scientificNameID: the LSID of the accepted name urn:lsid:marinespecies.org:taxname:109624</li></ul>", "<ul><li>scientificName: the accepted name Dinophysis fortii</li><li>scientificNameID: the LSID of the accepted name urn:lsid:marinespecies.org:taxname:109624</li></ul>"], "answer_text": "You should provide the taxon name as recorded in the dataset even if it is not the valid name. OBIS uses WoRMS as it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s taxonomic backbone and can get the accepted name an all other taxonomic information from there. Using the original name ensures traceability (you store the same as the one which was originally recorded). Moreover taxonomy is not stable: a taxon name which is considered to be an invalid synonym of one species to today, may be a valid taxon name tomorrow; using the original name ensures that you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t need to modify the dataset every time taxonomy changes.", "correct_answer": 1}, {"question": "When a Scientific Name is in WoRMS, but the taxonomic status is unaccepted (synonym), I can use the WoRMS LSID of the unaccepted name.", "answers": ["True", "False"], "answer_text": "OBIS indeed uses the information from WoRMS and will add occurrences to the current accepted name.", "correct_answer": 0}, {"question": "The OBIS quality control process focuses on:", "answers": ["Checking for possible errors in the species nomenclature.", "Uploading the data into the IPT.", "Checking for possible errors in taxonomy, geographic coordinates, depth, and data formats.", "Checking the number of records present in an Occurrence Core file."], "answer_text": "", "correct_answer": 2}]